# Ethan Pang

ethanp5@berkeley.edu (669) 262-5845 linkedin.com/in/ethanpang5 ethanpang5.github.io

#### **SUMMARY**

Third year student at UC Berkeley pursuing a B.A. in Computer Science and actively searching for a software engineering internship. Demonstrated strengths in web development, algorithms, object-oriented programming, data structures, data engineering, and ML through projects, courses, and work experience.

## **EDUCATION**

# University of California, Berkeley

June 2020 - May 2023

B.A. Computer Science | GPA: 3.8/4.0 | CAA Leadership Award Recipient | Upsilon Pi Epsilon (CS Honor Society) Relevant Coursework

- Data Structures and Algorithms/Efficient Algorithms
- Intro to Artificial Intelligence/Intro to Machine Learning/Principles of Data Science:
- Computer Architecture/Designing Information Devices & Systems (EECS)/Discrete Mathematics and Probability Theory

#### **SKILLS**

- Java, Python, C, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Swift, SQL, RISC-V
- React.js, Next.js, Node.js, Firebase, Chakra.ui, Bootstrap
- Data engineering, data pipeline, data analysis, data modeling, data inference
- PyTorch, scikit-learn, ML workflow, numpy, pandas, neural networks, CNNs, classification, regression
- Agile, Jira, AWS RDS, Android, IOS, Linux, git, Jupyter Notebook, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Solidworks

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Frontend Developer - Web Development at Berkeley

September 2021 - Present

- Developing websites for external clients in the industry using React.js and Next.js frameworks, Chakra.ui styling library, and HTML/CSS
- Engaging in the agile development process in collaboration with a project team

#### Course Staff: CS61B - UC Berkeley

June 2022 - August 2022

- Taught as course staff for UC Berkeley's core data structures course, CS61B
- Prepared and presented supplementary mini-lectures to students to reinforce concepts and guided students through practice questions to solidify understanding of material
- Answered student questions about assignments, and provided real time debugging help with projects

# Data Engineering PM - Public Editor

September 2021 - May 2022

- Analyzed user performance with a moving-average algorithm to allow the platform to score users' credibility
  - Built data processing pipeline with pandas and stored user info in AWS MySQL database

#### Course Staff: CS61B - UC Berkeley

June 2021 - August 2021

## Mini Git Clone with Java

February 2021 - April 2021

- Created a version control system based off of git using Java
- Implemented common commands (commit, checkout, merge, push, pull, etc.) following git's specifications
- Allowed creation, deletion and modification of actual files on the system via the command line interface

### **FIRST Tech Challenge Robotics**

August 2016 - June 2020

- Built robots to compete in competitions using purchased, machined and 3D printed parts
- Used Java and Android Studio to program the robot to perform autonomously through sensor readings, computer vision, and mathematical algorithms and to respond to human input via a physical gaming controller
- Organized and lead team outreach efforts to teach public STEM workshops and mentor other robotics teams
- Advanced to World Championships three of four years and served as team Co-Captain in the 2019-2020 season

#### **AWARDS/HONORS**

- California Alumni Association Leadership Award
- Upsilon Pi Epsilon: Nu Chapter (CS Honor Society)
- Chinese Student Association Officer: Webmaster